CAROLINE CHEN

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

516-384-6737

carolinecaroline@gmail.com carolinechen.io

linkedin.com/in/caroline-chen-wd

SKILLS

- JavaScriptHTML
- jQuery
- Git
- AngularJS
- OpenText
- React
- Wordpress
- Sass
- Dreamweaver
- o CSS
- Photoshop

EDUCATION

General Assembly Washington, DC

Web Development Immersive & Front End Web Development 2017

George Washington University Washington, DC

Master of Forensic Sciences 2007

Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science in Biological Sciences with an additional major in Psychology 2005

ACTIVITIES

Instructor Washington Improv Theater

2015 - Present

Webmaster
District Improv
2017 - Present

ABOUT

Innovative front end developer with 2 years experience building responsive, user-focused websites. As an intellectually curious individual with a drive for solving problems, I combine my analytical background in forensic science with my passion for creativity to build sites and applications that are informative, time-saving, and unique.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

O Federal Reserve Board, Washington DC

Jr. Web Designer/Developer

2017 - Present

- Worked with team to redevelop company intranet site
- Posted time-sensitive content to company public site
- Updated 3 internal sites to make modern and responsive
- Assisted site owners in troubleshooting and updating content
- Created solutions to streamline and automate processes
- Served as team representative in monthly UX meetings
- Followed best practices for 508 compliance for accessibility

Bode Cellmark Forensics, Lorton, VA DNA Analyst

2006 - 2017

- Processed labwork for thousands of DNA samples
- Performed data analysis and issued reports
- Performed technical review of hundreds of cases
- Managed projects to ensure deadlines were met
- Trained new analysts

PROJECTS

Sample Tracker

How can we easily track forensic sample processing in a lab?

- Created a proof-of-concept application with an intuitive user interface to allow users to input and edit sample information
- Implemented visual cues so users can quickly determine next steps in the processing workflow

Cache

How can I easily track my personal finances?

- Developed a responsive interface to allow users to create and manage savings accounts for easy personal budgeting
- A full-stack application with full create-read-update-delete capabilities